hello I'm your host David Bernard and
with me today Revenue cat CEO Jacob
iding Our Guest today is Franchesco
santon the CEO and co-founder of Mojo an
app that enables everyone to easily
create top-notch videos for Instagram
and Tik Tok on the podcast we talked
with Franchesco about how Mojo grew to
over 1 million in ARR the most impactful
pricing and pay wall experiments and why
it's important to choose complexity
instead of just letting it happen hey
Franchesco thanks so much for joining us
on the podcast today hey super excited
to be there and Jacob nice to have you
on the podcast today I'm here David I'm
ready to talk about subscriptions and
with a person I've known for a very long
time so nice it's exciting so speaking
of long time I did want to kind of go
back in history a little bit we don't
always dig into the history of apps and
founding stories and stuff but you've
got an especially cool one so tell me
about what you doing way back in 2013
and how that kind of brought you to
founding Mojo yeah I think like the
relationship that I have with apps and
video is long I think a bit like jackob
I started like as an iOS Developer and
an entrepreneur but around mobile apps
and in 2013 for the first time I was an
employee as an iOS Developer I met my
co-founder there but also my team was
great because I was working with mat
from photo room which I think is also a
hug fan of cat yeah like me we did work
on this cool video editing app together
and with of course a small ninja startup
team and we got acquired by GoPro so we
continued to work on video that became
the official GoPro app right for a while
or yeah exactly we transformed like the
replay app into the quick app yeah which
is still is the base of the GoPro app
every time I open yeah I think but it
was also a lot of fun story both in term
of engineering and product like the
transformation of a product into another
one was really at the time also fun
story they also acquired splice another
video at the exact same time so we had
to mer that had to be yeah we could do a
whole podcast on the social and
emotional dynamics of that I'm sure also
GoPro was already public at the time
right yeah exactly and we got some
shares but unfortunately that went
down public markets are tough you know
DJI funds but the brand is still like
amazing I love yeah I mean they still
make great cameras the software is
really good like I use the old app
whenever I live stream my race car races
I use the quick app to set up live
streaming straight from the GoPro to the
hot spot and all that so it's pretty
interesting even if the equity didn't
ban out it's need to still have the
impact right yeah
sure and the bigger impact and you kind
of brush over a little bit but it is you
were working with Matthew from photo
room who went on to found what's now one
of the biggest apps in photo you went on
to found Mojo which we're going to talk
about with a co-founder who was there uh
huge successful app and then the CTO at
hucking face was also there at the time
so you've got this like replay Mafia I
think that's true of a lot of startups
you know like the PayPal Mafia like when
you get a lot of really smart people
together have similar experiences and
then you also get a built-in network but
you guys probably can take some credit
for like France's reputation in AI right
like not all of it but like there is a
reputation that Paris specifically in
France has like after San Francisco it
might be like the most known hub for AI
right now and it's not in spite of this
right yeah I think like Jun M were like
the pioneers of actual applied AI in
France and they really paved the way and
we also got those new players like
Mistral we also got the poolside team
moved from I think the US to France so
yeah I think like right now uh but don't
start me about AI because we will never
end uping about NE mobile or I mean it
goes to show that like the folks that
are winning in this category or like
seem like way ahead in this category
didn't start last year they started a
decade ago right and we're building the
expertise and then the right moment
happens and then all of a sudden you
have a thing but yeah these Talent
density networks are really interesting
and our thing I strive to one day create
a revenue C Mafia That's My we're never
gonna leave Jacob come on man right yeah
that's what all you're stuck with me the
fun story is like egging face actually
not that I think about it and hello to
Clon and Julia they started as a mobile
app a chatbot like a tamagi like a
virtual friend so I think like at some
point the circle will close because I
think they should do it again it also
highlights how inter leave mobile and AI
is like I think there's been some people
being like mobile is over and apps are
over and AI is starting and it's like
they're the same thing like the the AI
Revolution is another app Revolution and
in some cases came very much from the
talent and like learnings of those you
know it's just a great form factor for
it so I think for AI I think something
that's never said enough I think like AI
simplify so many things that you can
make even more things in Mobile
especially on the creation side so you
know like consumption on mobile is
normal but creation and like Photo room
like Mojo I think like creation on
mobile will get much much bigger thanks
to Ai and we also have this kind of us
or european point of view but if you
think about even our top markets like
Brazil or Asia they don't even have
laptops on computer so if you bring like
that power into Mobile meaning that you
can do a lot more stuff with less and
fewer like interface so I didn't even
think about that that the leverage you
get out of like a textual interface gets
you much more different on a mobile
device than it does on a laptop where
like yeah maybe point and click is
actually pretty good right that's
interesting it highlights like the
constraints of human computer interfaces
right and that's actually probably where
a lot of our constraints Li today anyway
we're here to talk about apps so let's
yeah well and we're here to talk about
the story we already div down a pretty
deep rabbit hole but I want to resurface
and say you I think a lot of people
listening to this podcast whether
they're already working at an app
company or like dreaming of a side
project or whatever if you're working at
a huge company and you think you want to
start a little startup maybe go find a
cool app startup to join and find one of
those high density places and then go
start your startup after that it's
pretty cool how many people from that
team went on to found very successful
companies it's probably not a
coincidence yeah I can double down on
that just because just after uni I
immediately started my first two
companies in Mobile that I felt like
miserably but I learn a lot and once I
started to really join that really
talented team at stup Flix I've learned
so much that then starting a company
again was much easier and I don't spoil
also but I think like mobile and AI from
the previous funer of stupid fix maybe
they are also planning something Co
so nice and then to finish to close that
Loop a year after joining GoPro you and
your co-founder left GoPro and started a
new app and went through YC tell me a
little bit about that yeah basically
we're obsessed about going fast having
impact and having a lot of fun and so we
were always looking for like this
Innovative ID in creativity and the fun
part is also we did AI back then but it
was the previous wave that didn't really
took off deep learning and CNN and all
of this so we decided basically to make
like an animation app you could put 3D
text in the real world so augmented
reality we were a bit too early let's
say but we had so much fun and we
applied to YC but we were like at the
time French to YC was not like a big
thing so we were like not really
thinking that we had a realistic chance
but eventually we got in and we learned
so much and then we were followed by
Revenue cats I think the next batch and
then F the room not so long after yeah
around 2017 18 yeah and so you started
the augmented reality app and raised
money through YC and went through YC
with that and then pivoted yeah it was
odd because I think like and this is a
good lesson actually for the sub Club
basically what we've successfully done
with the augmented re app that was we
got like a wow effect so basically when
you started the app you will show
immediately like something that you
wouldn't think were possible with
technology so you will see your actual
text in 3D in the real world and that
was so cool we were also detecting
emotion and putting emojis automatically
so people were so hyped that they were
downloading the Apple out Apple was also
super hyped because the quality was
there and air of course was very
strategic for them but so we got like
those hundred of thousand of doll in the
few months and it's really really hard
to at some point acknowledge that you
have to shut down something like that so
basically the reason we did that and the
proxy metrics that we use and thanks to
YC is like you really have to do
something that people love first so no
matter like if you have like one million
users that just like your product and
don't come back you need to find those
100 users that are really dying for your
product and we couldn't crack any
engagement metrics like retention or
stickiness and we tried a lot of things
in AR we tried to really pivot inside
the app first so we did interactive
stuff during the 2018 World Cup with
life scores and a lot of things gaming
dancing we tried brainstorm on a lot of
things but at some point you have to
realize that it was too early for
augmented reality to take off and we
really recentered on our core beliefs
around video creation so good learnings
but really hard hard time when you go
back to zero and say okay now we have to
find an idea retention metrics I just
was talking to a very nent founder
yesterday who's just launching an app
and was like oh I think it's got legs or
whatever and I was like what's your
retention like that's what matters right
I don't care how many downloads you have
I don't care you've been featured it's
like how many people are using the app
how many people are coming back and then
if you're paying like how many people
are like renewing or paying is
interesting but also like renewing and
the thing is is you can't hide like you
can't hide that right if people aren't
loving your product they're not going to
keep opening it and I've been in that
world too where you're like you got
something you kind of try to like wander
around a local Maxima right which is
good eventually you find like okay you
try moving in as many orthogonal
directions as you can understand and
then if you don't see a big lift then at
some point you have to go like well we
need to jump somewhere else in the
distribution right I think a really good
way to think about that is do you have a
gimmick or do you have a product and a
gimmick can be fun and I start of
something right yeah yeah yeah it can be
the start of something but like it has
to turn into a product and I think you
can even and this is something to think
about even as you're kind of adding
features to an existing app that maybe
have some level of product Market fit is
that you know and I chased my tail a lot
with my launch in a Pro app because I
would get these big splashy launches
because we do something super Innovative
but then it wouldn't stick as like a
real feature it wasn't a real product it
was just something that got people hyped
got a lot of downloads but it wasn't a
real business it wasn't a real product
people wouldn't engage with it over time
people downloaded played with it for a
minute and moved on with their lives so
like you really got to build the
features and the products that people
are going to come back to to your point
Franchesca that you didn't have a
business people weren't engaging over
time and it's great that you figured out
that you needed to Pivot and like made
those hard choices yeah and Apple's love
can actually make this worse right yeah
like they it kind of artificially
inflate your Organics right that was the
main reason that we actually added like
subscription into Modo like from the
get-go right away I remember talking to
you about this yeah yeah as you said
like you have this kind of funel yeah of
course you need activation but we didn't
even had like a nonbing pay wall for a
few years because what we wanted to
measure is the actual interest and so at
some point of course you have to grow a
bit more so you put this pay wall into
General a dollar is a dollar right like
if you can capture a dollar you've
captured something measurable and real
and you can't really lie to yourself
right ex that the best proxy ever yeah
and even if it's small dollars right it
doesn't matter if you can move that up
now you have something measurable that
you know is like real and then like you
said like when it's time to actually
make money then you can start to think
about how to actually optimize for that
but there's some argument to like you
have to build a lot of stuff to justify
a subscription on day one but I mean not
that much stuff right like take one
really cool thing put it behind a pay
wall and see what you get there's no
harm in that you know I think some
people are embarrassed to like charge
for something not done but it's like
whatever people don't have to buy it
nobody's entitled to what you built
right we were very very embarrassed you
should be you should be it's good I mean
starting anything is embarrassing that's
the thing is like if you can't just
manage embarrassment for a really long
time we're probably not going to build
something so as you pivoted into Mojo
what did that early first launch of the
Mojo app look like yeah I think like
jaob said that like you have to be a bit
ashamed so we are like just pivoting and
we were funding story like should we
give back the money to investors or so
we took that call with our YC Partners
so Michael and gustaff they were like
almost laughing at us you know it's like
what are you talking we invested in you
not in your product that throw emojis
everywhere you know and basically the
first thing that they said and that I
say also as a business Angel and Coach
sometime is like it's never too early to
release your product right so I think we
took like still two full months a bit
more to build the first version that
what I called Alpha and we did a product
HT and basically that day we decided to
put subscription for the GetGo that's I
think the first time that I talk to
Jacob I remember we are just the two of
us micer and I plus an intern which is
now working on the n up and we were like
if on Day Zero we get one trial and at
that time the trial was 30 days because
we didn't want anyone to pay by accident
hav wanted to put like $1 a month a
subscription but we eventually s it to
10 and we like if we get one trial
period from one country that we don't
know so except us and France because of
friends maybe we will celebrate and we
got I think on the day Zero like 30
trials so EV was the app that we thought
was broken we we really thought that the
app was broken you couldn't like half of
the thing were glitchy but you can
provide value to people and what we
enabled people to do was actually like
much much easy than we didn't realize
that until the actual launch yeah I do
really think with ideas people are like
oh does this have legs like whatever
whatever and if you're like asking
yourself it's probably not even Revenue
cat it took a longer for a B2B thing to
get any sort of like positive feedback
but I could tell in conversations with
people and I could tell there was like
and stuff but for Consumer it pops like
if it's good enough it'll pop right now
can you build something sustaining and
differentiated that's a different
question but yeah often like you have
good signal on day Zero when something's
really really useful yeah and then
scoping ahead to today you shared with
me that Mojo now does over $1 million in
Mr has over 40 million downloads and
does that with a team of 30 so
incredibly Successful by most metrics
and so I wanted to kind of go through
some of the things that it took to get
there some of the experiments some of
what the team has done with such a small
team to build such a great business
around this kind of early app so I want
to start with pricing and pay walls and
like what are some of the bigger lessons
you've learned growing to this size
around pay walls yeah I think like pay
walls is a good example of things that
we did very late on because yeah we were
like every focused on the product but
yeah at some point you cannot take
things for granted right so of course
most of the value you capture is from
your product itself and from the value
that you provide to your users but at
some point you have to show them that
like I remember because the first signal
that we got was from the up store team
from Apple was like you're not pushing
your payroll enough and the first
payroll experiment that we did without
even changing the payroll was pting it
at the end of the onboarding which was
everyone was doing that but we were like
oh but they didn't try the app yet and
whatever but like but they have a trial
so the first actual like big experiment
that we had was like the onboarding
payroll and I think it accounts for most
of the trial even today and then slowly
like moving of course of the funnel of
impact so the payall position on top
then you want to iterate of course on
the payall design the payall kind of
layout and core Narrative of the payall
right do you want to use the kind of how
do you split that like how much do you
think about like visual aspects and like
the weights and things like that which
matter like they subconscious and
psychological things and then also how
do you think about what it's actually
saying what is the actual message yeah
so I think like we were super lucky at
some point to hire someone dedicated to
monetization mik I think he wrote a
great article on the r blog actually
about our experiment and the grow so
what we've done like as you said we are
like a small team so every decision
every focus is like you cannot spread
too much your attention and you really
have to be focused so what we've done is
basically do one quarter after another
focusing on those kind of prioritization
parts so first is like position of the
payall two is totally different pay
walls just try different pays one with a
video what we did is like mixing silver
bullets you know at any given point you
will hear from like oh you have to show
a video a simple like no a lot of text
and sometimes like scrolling sometimes
like you have to do like a trial
reminder putting the trial to go there's
so many kind of best practice that
change over time so just changing this
kind of big different concepts was
really helpful because you never know
with this kind of audience what will
work better then with done that a bit
more localized also into different
countries because I think it's also one
specificity that we have also as a
European company I think we all from the
get-go you have like this very
International worldwide view where like
I think us is like a third of revenues
only number one country yes but just a
third so then you always have to think
about all the countries so big layer CH
when one payall is working you can do
like smaller change within that and then
you do price testing right and really
changing the price and see what works
but it's OD because what I say is like
you should basically take two things
into consideration one is of course the
average revenue per user that you get
arpu but the other is like what is the
line with your product because some
product are more naturally aligned with
more like b2c distribution so you want
that to be a bit cheaper even if you
lose a bit of money starting maybe we
get it on the longer run and other you
want to focus on high quality user so
you want to charge a bit more and you
can look at different pricing on the
industry like video editing photo
editing and you will see basically where
you are in our case it was like charging
a bit more because also it was
profitable a bit more for us but also
targeting a bit more prummer users right
like small businesses and so on because
when you have a freemium app you get a
lot of free users and it's hard to
sometime they will pay but Canary and
it's hard to get all of the signal and
even now to be honest it's a problem
that we're still focusing on is like how
do you get your cor user base to pay the
right price without losing the benefit
of the other I mean that's just pricing
and packaging right are you doing like
any separation and teers or anything
like this now that's something that we
didn't try we didn't try basically what
we have still left in the monetization
side is trying the weekly we didn't try
trying the as you said changing the
limiting factor in any given price and
doing like
maybe yeah exactly what feature going
what plan businesses actually they often
like you do user interviews they say I
don't understand why you charge like 60
70 a year and sometime like up store
reviews like wow what this price is like
yeah right makes sense well it's like
the product generates massively
different Surplus value depending on how
it's being used right and so one of my
gifts at Revenue cat is like I kind of
can understand the value generated to
some degree right and measure but like
for Consumer apps it's very different
right I think it's one of the core
challenges of doing price discrimination
Matthew talked about this a couple years
ago and he's on the podcast but this has
been a big part of their strategy too is
like differentiating between these
different use cases and like trying to
like hit them with the right price
points and I think as we see more we
were talking about the power of mobile
first tooling at the top of the call and
I think like more and more apps are
going to see this where the breakout
apps if you're not like a du lingo if
you're not like a massive consumer brand
the other path is going to be this like
bet to B2B prosumer path so I think
there's a lot to be figured out there
because it's complex right yeah anytime
you're helping somebody make money you
can charge more money yeah it's Surplus
value right like you're capturing
Surplus value and for somebody who's
just like random person posting to Tik
Tok or Instagram there's not a lot of
value for them personally in their
Grandma seeing at least not something
they translate easily to cash right yeah
exactly and those are the people who are
like $60 a year to like post better
videos to Instagram this is insane it's
so funny how that affects so many people
like how mad that makes I probably said
this on poet times but if somebody isn't
mad at you about your pricing your
pricing is wrong right like like if you
make everybody happy you're definitely
under pricing right and so it's about
strategically deciding how many people
you want to make mad and who you want to
make mad and it's actually a good signal
if people are complaining about your
price a little bit right because you can
always take that information adjust it
and things like this but the last thing
you want to do is especially when you're
on the outset is like set your price
point super low because then like not
only have you like left a lot of money
on the table you've also set the
perception that your product's not worth
that much right and so like if the
developer saying it's only worth a
dollar why am I going to Value this
thing right you want a offense story
about that sure yeah we I think about it
I got a user telling us that we should
charge way more so like they end up with
less users using Modo and the the pro
like the top templates so they could
stand up
interesting like you should charge even
10 like because some people they create
even agencies out of modu like they will
hire like three Freelancers and they
will charge the business we should give
people sub Club challenges David bit but
like your sub Club challenge is this
create a $100 a month skew that's just
full of exclusivity luxury templates
right I would be really interested to
see what that experiment yields right
and tradeoff because again it's like
there are people for whom whom that
exclusivity has a lot of value right and
you can capture some of that I think so
it's the whole lvmh model right like
just charge for exclusivity it' be very
French right of course yeah exactly as
French we love design we love Tech and
science you know and maths and luxury
and exclusivity so it's fine so it
sounds like you did raise your prices
significantly did that have a huge
impact on the business yeah it did I
think IP increased like in the range of
plus 50% at some point so yeah it had
like a huge impact with all the testing
and and sometimes it's like just I think
like the latest experiment that we had
is like we didn't realize that our
turkey inflation was eating them and the
price point there and whatever so Mikel
had a test like a few weeks ago that we
roll out with like plus 100% there ipu
because inflation and all of this so
sometime it's just like you don't see
how much this can impact your users and
also positively and even now I think
like we didn't the logic of it like the
core as you said like how do you split
because every time we increase the price
we also make those part of the user that
tried the product but then at some point
they don't get enough value so they CH
more so if we had like several price
points I think would be the perfect
thing but it's also we are humble enough
to know that it's hard to manage like
several price point and TI it's hard to
manage because it's complex and if it's
complex for you your customers are also
going to be confused and that in itself
will create downward pressure on
conversions if it's like hard to buy and
I think that's the chall and for the
engineering team and you know everything
that you do then you have to think about
oh is it t one two and matrics and all
of this there are like two kind of
companies or product or developers like
the one that's always say that it's easy
and sometime I'm a bit like this and
sometime you also humbled down by the W
it looked easy but actually this simple
stuff like it should take like two days
but it took like a thousand little ropes
right that like hold you down over time
as you build like I think about us we've
had one two three four five we're on
like our SE we have like seven plans
over three iterations and that's not a
ton for Consumer especially if you're
like doing it in different countries and
stuff but even that of thinking about
all the transition States between those
different things and like why and like
not only do you have to make that work
commercially so that you're like oh what
happens to people on this plan to
compare to the new plan and all that
stuff but you also have to make it work
technically right like what happens
Technically when this person wants to go
to this plan and then thirdly
operationally which is like how do we
read that data how do we put it into our
chart like all of that stuff it the
complexity grows so like we push
experimentation and trying stuff but
like I do think there is a limit to the
amount of complexity unless you have a
really good process for like trying and
shutting down things and and clearing it
out but like I'm curious like what would
you say like percentage of your R&D
resources go into like monetization and
building that stuff versus building new
product do you have like a split in mind
or is it like one quarter we focused on
this one quarter we focused on this like
how we just have one guy on M just one
guy just going got super cat R yeah I
got it no but it's true we're using
Revenue cat a lot from the get-go I
think like at the time it was like super
controversial because people were think
like it's easy and that but yeah we were
talking about this before the call like
you were a very early
adopter yeah because I think like that's
exactly the kind of thing that from the
outside is like oh yeah it's super easy
the SDK it's getting better maybe the
startkit part but it's definitely
different now than it was in 2018 for
sure yeah yeah but it was still good
enough you know for you to do things
easily but you always have this kind of
if you want to be really into excellent
and have this great experience you
always lack a bit nice touch make it to
walk perfectly yeah and even today with
storit 2 as easy it as is you said you
launch the MVP of Mojo in two months
you're not going to launch an MVP in two
months build yeah if you're building out
your own subscriptions and pay walls and
everything else at least like in a
future proof way we're transition to the
ad segment but we were talking about how
in the early days the early adopters
really had to be Believers like they had
to have as much conviction as you do
that this is a good idea that you don't
need to convince them and it's like
going back to your first launch of Mojo
it's like that's who you're looking for
you're looking for those first couple
users who get it and they can see
through how bad it is and see through
like all of it and still understand it
and the other you know crossing the chm
to Turkey and like all those other
things like really can wait you really
just want to find those like couple and
you were definitely of that first couple
I think you were in our first 100 apps
right but like every single one of those
people kind of had to have a real belief
in Revenue cat and then over time we
were talking before the call it's now
become the opposite where it's often you
see people being like Oh don't do
anything else right it was very
non-consensus at the beginning which is
true to some degree for all tools right
like I think we're seeing it now with
like generally Ai and like when to use
LMS and not and like all of this stuff
right it's very you know and then at
some point it'll switch to everybody
being like why are you doing this the
stupid way you know yeah but you were
talking about pricing and having a
dedicated person and like what kind of
focus
you have on monetization and the split
between like product monetization we
can't of Chase a rabbit hole but I
wanted to get back to that I had an
opportunity to sh my company David I
cannot leave it I cannot pass he I
started the sh it's my fault but uh I
want to get back to that because I'd
love to hear your thinking about like
how much iteration you put into the
monetization side of things versus like
Jacob was asking versus product and how
you balance that when there is so much
low hanging fruit and constantly
iterating on pricing and packaging but
like you got to have a product to sell
too it's like all these things are a
tough balance yeah for us what worked
well so far is really to put that like
with no sponsorship intended and I can
also quot super W to make that a bit
Heaven because we use that for the pays
but if you like get the right tooling
and the right person that is obsessed
about that then you can iterate like a
lot and Mikel is doing like a lot of
experiment is's really dedicated to that
gross part and monetization pay wall
pricing onboarding CRM we don't do yet
we might do a bit more with m so yeah
from time to time like International
expansion it gets like a one developer
when we need for experimentation but
most of it actually can do it like by
himself are they a technical background
or engineer or like a growth marketer
like what's not necessarily but he has
really like this data mind is from a
Czech Republic and with like this kind
of structural approach with like
everything is documented in the notion
all experiment and this is working very
well but for the product part too yeah
you're right because I think and coming
back to the fr and maybe an advice for
the creative space I think like the sub
Club listener can be divided between the
people that have more maybe business
side and want to try apps and make it
and with AI today I think it's really a
new El Dorado you know like kind of God
but there are also a lot of more in
developers that are this craft and I
think like that's originally our
developers and for those I think in
Creative space never forget that we are
lucky enough to kind of build product
where people would create something that
they would inherently share so either
like with the watermark or better with
Modo at the beginning I think until like
several
hundred, per month we spend zero do in
ads why because we invented basically
the animated posters in stories like it
didn't exist when people saw like a
random guy posting like this super great
video like animated poster on Instagram
they were like asking in the DMs like
how did you do that and that's not you
and people were just referring the app
without any like referral mechanism so
that's also kind of a just I wanted to
give a bit of Hope to developer is like
because it's hard often to know how to
put eort like where do you put for like
all in ASO UA versus like product but if
you really are like into the right
product angle you can make it by having
something like inherently Superior as
long as it's like interesting
distribution Channel you want the output
of your app to be visible and if you
have that think about how you can
leverage that to get like some well it's
just much more efficient right than
having to spend even so you have to
spend to like get it right and then
obviously acquisition is a very Dollar
in dollar and 10 out or whatever like
it's not a highly leveraged game versus
having you used to call kfactor I don't
know if people still call that but like
how many downloads does a download beet
but building that into your product from
the beginning it will make a difference
and like you don't have to do it I
actually would suggest not doing it in a
way that's like very clearly just like
an afterthought right it's just like oh
share your scorecard or like whatever
like that's fine but what you want to do
is like think about a way like your
product is made for sharing right so
it's kind of built in and that's the
case with a lot of like photo editing
stuff maybe some more than others or
like creation stuff but you can think
about it in other aspects right like
invites are like a famous in Social like
invites are the thing which I don't know
if you saw they're shutting off free
access to contact books so we'll never
see another viral social app again I
think but yeah like thinking about how
does the like core Loop of the app and
then there's really not a clear line
there's maybe monetization but growth is
actually bigger than that maybe it's a
good chance to like ask about this so
yeah you said initially you didn't have
any growth spend and stuff like that
which I would recommend we talk about
things that like hide your lack of
product Market fit dumping a bunch of
money in acquisition is a good way to
convince yourself you have something
when you don't thank you right so get
off the ground and make sure you have
something but like you go from that like
couple hundred thousand to like million
what were the moves and plays that
allowed you to get people driven into
the app so from this organic push from
the users and also Apple we got also a
lot featured so again and I'm super
grateful for the App Store and also the
App Store itself for existing I'm a huge
fan no because it's true because before
if you remember about the other stores
like even like publishing a game on any
video game console was super OD like
Distributing a software on PC like was
super OD and the App Store is really
intrinsically worldwide and all of this
so This Is Why I'm talking that not just
to thanks the the Apple team but also
because we are like this worldwide
approach we had this spikes in countries
that organically we didn't spend any
money but then at some point we got like
our first user acquisition guy anony
that's really changed the way that we
leverage this kind of smart acquisition
in the fact that you can have from Apple
search ads also the kind of more broad
meta and Tik Tok approach you can get AI
approach of course Esa Network also
changed the game a lot but user
acquisition was our first let's say
nonorganic Ross level with kind of an
approach that was still mostly relying
on this kind of organic Factor so what
we did is like at the time it was still
a thing to pay the influencers to
publish in their own accounts rather
than use their content to ads so we
tried like in several countries to do
like those campaign they were not like
profitable but they enabled like in some
count I remember like Brazil for example
Brazil we did the campaign it was like a
fail small Spike and this but a few
weeks later we got the initial spar
enough and it's still among of top five
even top three countries nowadays So
Paid acquisition like influencers and
thing and then that turned paid into a
bigger scale with all of the challenges
right gross data of course because with
escad network even with mmps how much
effort do you put in trying to like
match attribution these days the core
thing first that we gave up in a way
that we don't do like pltv and stuff we
push a lot more the yearly plan to make
that much easier so the idea being it's
like you can get the payback on a cohort
and then you want to get the pay back in
30 days kind of is how do you cohort do
you like without finger printing or this
you just go by country or you break it
down to a demo or how so the first split
and that's is the easiest part right you
split by country you split by platform
also of course IOS and Android that's
sure now we went back to and depending
on the day-to-day versus longer budget
allocation you can do like on the
day-to-day it's more like an let's say
we attribute the subscription by the
date of atand let's say trial start with
the atand of that week but on the longer
run we do that Court based so basically
the user acquired by a certain amount of
AD spand are Blended by country and also
of course country you have some like
shifting window cohorts where you're
like okay we're just going to say that
the ad money we spent in this period
created these trials like whether or not
that's accurate or not doesn't matter
but it's maybe a good enough approach to
make sure you're not bankrupting the
company and yeah exactly and maybe I got
some future requests for you oh yeah
yeah hit me I think like what we're
using we're actually using Revenue cat
as one of the source of new users
something that think I was talking with
B of grow lately we're like thinking
about the way to attribute actually new
users or displaying should be maybe
hybrid approach where you could
basically say you count as a new user at
least for attribution for that sliding
window CS but you could have like let's
say that a user is inactive for a
certain amount of time let's say 30 days
then you come back to the new period
because what happen is like when you
spend a lot of money you increase the
passort because you of retargeting
because of a lot of that and some of
them maybe unin they already have the
app installed but they still exactly
they already have then sometime somehow
with iCloud and nowadays I think like
even without uninstalling because people
I'm not sure they ever uninstall apps
again with the automatic offloading and
stuff like that so I think like
something like ibrid is something that
we want to try in the next
yeah the world has shifted so much in
attribution I think the thing is is that
the new world the new like
fingerprintless world has made it so
there's so much less value in the
technology there which is also why
nobody's rushed into to solve it because
like there's not a huge business to
build there but for us thinking about it
there's things we can doin I'll just say
we're thinking about it one of the
things that you mentioned to me when we
were prepping for this conversation was
don't fall into the product Le growth
trap so a lot of what we talked about
early on was product Le grow growth but
then you did start venturing into paid
user acquisition but what did you mean
by that don't fall into the product Le
growth trap what I mean is basically you
have to really know your strength and
know what are not your strength and what
are your weaknesses and basically you
can have like three buckets think that
are are inherently bad at I can give
some example for me I'm bad at Ops I'm B
at things that are boring I'm B at a lot
of things so I will not be like on like
a regional Opex business like delivery
app or whatever I will be super bad I
will be the worst CEO ever what we are
good at modro is like the product and
the tech and this kind of angle you have
this angle this leverage and this Market
which is you create video you create the
most beautiful video it's inant but then
when you're kind of in the middle and
you're like more like with a regular app
or business Centric if you don't have
this core product leg it's not by adding
like a refer or whatever that you will
think that you made it right right and I
think Jacob said it like it's not
something that you add later on that you
fake it of course it's always good to do
a bit but don't think that you will
crack it after a while and if it's not
in the core DNA either in the
distribution of your app or your content
that you create out of your app or the
strength in your team so what I meant by
don't fall in the product Le gross is
product Le gross is always kind of shiny
you mean just make the product better
and they will come right yeah exactly
but also if you're like a business
person accept it and work on paid and
make that the best LTV on K and beat
people on user acquisition and pay
worlds testing even more and don't fall
too much into oh when we build like this
six months feature of referal the app
will grow up or when we need like the
sharing those cards yeah sure but nobody
shares even their dingo card or whatever
you know there are a few counter
examples of apps that don't focus on
anything else and just can win through a
good product but there's always
something there's always either Apple
love or it's something inherently viral
or it's something inherently unique they
do I think of Anki the like flash card
app that's really popular it's not even
a paid app I don't think but like they
just built a really good product but
like maybe not a really good business
but like or maybe maybe Craigslist is a
good example right of where it's Works
some counter examples of where they
haven't had to really think about growth
but those are outliers you're not
Craigslist like you're not one of these
apps that just gets lucky probably being
somebody who did that a lot for some
years at Elevate we wandered the
Wilderness on before we really dipped
our toes into like leaning into a growth
engine you know and realizing the
products is good maybe as it's going to
get within some parameters and it had
some sort of product Market fit but like
we weren't going to double our retention
through new features right it was
probably some sort of inherent level
that it gets to and then you have to
figure out where your leverage actually
lies so yeah I was really surprised and
you kind of touched on it earlier that
even at a million plus in Mr you aren't
doing CRM you're not doing some of the
basics that
blg but what you're talking about is
focus right and so yeah maybe you're not
doing CRM but you have a whole person
dedicated to constantly doing
monetization experiments and paywall
experiments and kind of looking and it
sounds like a lot of the success of Mojo
is like looking at what's working and
being introspective about why it's
working and doubling down on those
strengths versus looking at what you're
weak in and overly focusing on those
weaknesses it's true at some point you
still have to accept you know and that's
why we probably will do a bit of CRM at
some point but it's exactly that you
know CRM is we have like even the top
five languages in modo is like does not
account for more than two third of the
user base so if you think about CRM and
scaling that to different languages and
having the impact Serum is probably
single digit grow so that you can
activate with a lot of effort yeah so we
were a bit reluctant and we pushed that
back of course at some point you need to
as the company grow and is a bit more
established you need to take those kind
of okay that's serum card we need to
activate it now to kind of have this bit
of growth but yeah if you do that too
early also my biggest fear and I think
like I didn't overcome it yet because
also video Market is changing fast and
especially right now in Ai and moo to be
honest I don't consider it as a success
yet because I think that's the future of
video editing is AI all the market is
disrupt and I love it personally so but
everything is yet to be built I'm always
afraid to lean away from the signal of
product Market Fe
so it's kind of also coming back to my
own fears I think and to overcome that a
bit sometime because I need also to be a
better I think business person and less
sometime of a product guy don't listen
to him I think Jacob's framing earlier I
really liked I'm going to steal this
from you Jacob but I forget exactly how
you said it but it was like you're going
to piss off some people with your price
the important thing is to choose who you
piss off with your price I think this
applies to building a company is that
you're going to have complexity choose
your complexity and you want to choose
that complexity based on Leverage and so
right now you recognize that CRM is very
complex and is relatively low leverage
like it's going to be hard to squeeze
double digigit growth out of CRM and
it's really complex so instead you're
choosing the complexity of building into
the AI future of video editing that's a
very complex thing to build you're
choosing to do something very complex
but you're doing something complex
that's very high leverage that's going
to be the foundation of the business
moving forward and I think that's kind
of a great it's differentiated too right
like do complexity that other people
can't for people that didn't read the
piece of Po grah how to do great work I
strongly encourage you to read that
immediately because I think that the
core thing also that focus on the
problem that you really are passionate
to solve and that's of course is makes
up for a lot right yeah you know as we
scale too and like debating with Miguel
like sure if I spent time on every part
of the business like there's something I
could improve but like if we let every
single part of the business that isn't
working exactly how we'd like into our
brains we'll be paralyzed and we won't
move forward on the thing that got us
here in the first place and so I think
that's one of the learnings and I don't
think that really happens until you're
maybe at kind of your guys' scale and
above where there's edges of the Empire
that you can't see anymore as a founder
and you have to just be okay with it
being how it is right there's the thing
is like oh just you can let fires burn
but almost worse is you just don't even
know if it's a fire or not you're like
could be a fire could be fine I don't
really know right don't like to ask
Jacob I think that every other week you
get like this kind of stress as like w
this fire is burning but I think like I
getting more and more like okay with
those you know this St and this but I
think like the biggest challenge as a
App Maker fer or whatever I think is in
there and to change yourself to kind of
perceive things differently to really I
want to put that on phasis like at some
point for the same level of information
you will look at everything is not the
way I want and like the week after
nothing drastically change and you think
oh we're doing good yeah yeah yeah yeah
the same inputs the same inputs you
start to realize like how much of it is
reception bias like how you're feeling
that day I don't think that's ever
stopped right it's like a constant
oscillation between like we're so back
it's so over right over and over and
again and I think the only thing that
can come with years is just realizing
that the troughs are just as transient
as the Peaks just ride them out try not
to quit when you're in a trough and keep
going I don't think I can stand behind
that enough in terms of and for people
at all stages of the journey if you're
the beginning if you're at the end or
like whatever like you're good at
something and like you can probably
build anything but the best thing you're
going to build is the thing you're good
at you maybe don't get to choose that
like I didn't get to choose in at
purchases is the thing I was good at
it's just kind of what happened and
maybe there's an argument for like oh
I've had a different passion for
something else but at the end of the day
performing and being good at something
that you created is probably more
satisfying than something you have a
passionate about but has no legs right
doesn't go anywhere so anyway we went
from user acquisition to philosophy real
fast on this episode of sub Club you
also have to choose which weaknesses to
fill in I think is that you know Like
You Jacob it's like you came to revenue
cat and you coated a lot of it and you
were very in the weeds and then at some
point you did have to choose to go down
the company building path and I've seen
you build the skills of people
management and Company management and
like you do have to fill in some of the
gaps that you don't like doing but again
it's like find people who are good at
the things that you're not good at but
then also choose the things you're going
to fill in and get better at versus like
you can't be good at everything so
recognize that and then don't try to be
good at everything but pick the things
you want to get better at and then find
ways to work around the things you
aren't High lever fre to get better at
or aren't going to move the business
forward whatever else yeah I would like
to share advice but then I think that
would imply I've figured something out
which I haven't I do miss coding though
I do I don't know if I was ever as that
good of a programmer but like I do think
I was probably a better programmer than
I'm not gonna say it than I'll ever be
as a CEO but there's a part of me that
thinks that I'm sure you franisco too
you think the same thing right like I'll
never feel as skilled or as capable as I
was when I was 24 years old and like
ripping code out all day believe it or
not during Christmas I took my phone and
I use ret AI to call the API of
replicate to batch AI to fine tune some
parameters I was happy just to see those
line of codes you know but it's like I
don't know about you but not only have I
stopped doing code I had to kind of
realize like I'll never be as good as I
was right like I'm taking too long of a
break but we can pretend it's fine
because we are the cosos like I get to
live vicariously through everybody else
who gets to ship I mean it's just it's
fun to build things that do things right
it's fun to build things that like do
things and like if you can find joy in
that then it almost doesn't matter
matter right you can find joy in just
winning and building and making
customers happy and showing up and being
useful right that's the AR SPS book be
useful right just being useful is
satisfying as a human being so anyway
this has been the sub Club career advice
and life philosophy hour but hopefully
it's
compelling this is super fun I I think
it's a great place to wrap up anything
else you wanted to share Franchesca as
we wrap up first thank you a lot for
this discussion not only interesting but
also a great moment and I think that's
something that we can celebrate and be
grateful to I think it's very important
and also maybe a piece of advice to the
people creating apps also because it's
my duty to do so on social media please
try to create more content consistently
so not just use Modo any other app but I
think like one of the secrets is like
the podcast is a good illustration of
that those people building apps you have
so many things to tell so many stories
to tell and not every one of them of
course can go into podcast and be lucky
as me so more and more what we see on
social media is like people sharing
their stories by themselves and not just
creators more and more like business
owner like even like I don't know like
restaurant owners butchers that would be
my piece of advice for people creating
project like find a way to share what
you're passionate about and social media
is a great way to get your first users
sometimes so piece of sponsored moment
awesome well thanks again for joining us
this was such a fun chat thank
you thanks so much for listening if you
have a minute please leave a review in
your favorite podcast player you can
also stop by chat. sub club.com to join
our private community
[Music]